Guide to the Margaret Meier Collection of Extreme Right Ephemeral Materials, 1930-1980
Department of Special Collections
- Series 1. Subject Files
  - Let Freedom Ring (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Letters to the Editor -Clipped by M. M. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - H.E. Lewis (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Liberty Amendment (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Liberty Lobby (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Liberty Lobby (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Liberty Lobby -literature (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Life Line (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Loyalty Oath (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Mayflower Congregational Church (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Dr. W.S. McBirnie (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - E.D. McEathron (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - McGuffey Readers (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Carl McIntire (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Medicare (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Mrs. Frances Meehan - Greater L.A. Citizens' Council (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Mrs. Frances Meehan (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Margaret and Herbert Meier (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Meier -correspondence (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Meier -correspondence (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Meier -MM's notes (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Meier -MM's names from American Opinion (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Meier -personal (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Mental Health (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Mental Health (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Minuteman Books (mat'ls collected at bookstore) (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Minute Men (militia) (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Minute Women (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Moderate Democrats (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Monrovia Anti-Communist Week (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Monrovia School Board (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Mothers' Crusade (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - MOTOREDE (Movement to Restore Decency) (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Senator George Murphy (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - NAACP (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - National Anti-Communism League (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - National Council of Churches (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - National Council of Churches of Christ (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - National Guard - Paisley (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - National States Rights Party (racist org.) (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - National Groups (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - National Groups (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - National Groups (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Rev. Paul Neipp - Lutheran (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Network of Patriotic Letter Writers (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Network of Patriotic Letter Writers (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Network of Patriotic Letter Writers (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - New Left (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - New and Religious Right - Clippings late 1970's-1980's (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Madame Ngo Dinh Nhu - sister-in-law of Pres. Ngo, South Vietnam (Box 22, Folder 1)
    All materials classified by date are chronologically filed here, as follows
  - 1939 -Clippings (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - 1930s-40s -Pamphlets (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - 1930s-40s -Anti-semitism literature from the Aryan Bookstore. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - 1930s-40s -Hollywood and the Left (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - 1930s-40s -Hollywood Anti-Nazi League for the Defense of American Democracy (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - 1939 -publications (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - 1961 -Literature from the Progressive BookshopApril 1961 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - 1960-66 -Clippings (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - 1980s -Clippings (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Richard Nixon --Arcadia Chair (Nixon for 1962 Governor Campaign, 1962) (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Nixon - Key Chairman (Nixon for Governor Campaign)1962 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Nixon Lists (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Nixon -China protest (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - "None Dare Call it Reason" (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - "None Dare Call It Treason" - A Texan Looks at Lyndon [Johnson] - book by John Stormer and Reaction (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Thomas Noonan (candidate for Congress) (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Thomas Noonan (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Obscenity (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Obscenity and CA State Assembly (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Revilo P. Oliver (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Revilo P. Oliver (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Organizational Research Association (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Overstreet (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Palo Alto Clinic Letter1969 Sept (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets A: Alert Americans Assoc. First National Directory of "Rightest" groups, Publications...--Amendments to the Constitution...to be submitted to the Electors of the State of California at the General Election Tuesday, Nov.6, 1962.--American View Vol. III, No. 8Feb. 1964--America's Future Pamphlets: Rosalie M. Gordon. Nine Men against America. Communist tactics...strategy...objectives. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Pamphlets B:---Brain-washing, a synthesis of the Russian Textbook on Phychopolitics [sic];--Rev. Edward F. Brophy. The "Brotherhood" Religion- Is it Anti-Christian?;--Business Man Looks at Communism (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlets -C:--California Homeowner, Feb. 1964; --California State Platform- Platform of the American Independent Party c.1978; --California Democratic State Central Comm. Far Right in the Far West. (2 copies);--Christian Anti-Communism Crusade. What can I do?--Church and Race Vol.1, No. 4, Aug. 1963;--Classics Record Library. American Folk Songs and Ballads;--Cold War Council, Bulletin No. 2-A Christian Crusade Publication; Investigation of the Black Muslims by the Comm. On Un-American Activities State of Louisiana. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Pamphlets C:--Committee of Public Records 20.5% 1411 --Protestant Episcopal Rectors. Reprinted 1960 by Circuit Riders, Inc;--Constitution (Fundamental Law) of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics;--Conspiracy! An Expose of Soviet Agents in America (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Pamphlets D-H:--US Sen. James O. Eastland. Is the Supreme Court Pro-Communist?;--Edison Electric. Let's Look at...Government in the Power Business;--Myron C. Fagan. The Eisenhower Myth;--Division of Fair Employment Practices. Fair July-Aug. 1963 Employment Newsletter. No. 14;--Freedom House. Soviet Crimes and Khruschev's Confessions;--Morgan Harris. The Peace System ca.1962 and the War System. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Pamphlets I-N:--Impact in the News Aug. 1968--Bill McClanahan and Herc Ficklen, Freedom Cartoons;--Marx and Engels. Manifesto of the Communist Party;--V.I. Lenin. Religion;--National Association of Manufacturers. Your Government, What do you know about it?;-- National Association of Manufacturers. A Tax Climate for Economic Growth. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Pamphlets N-R:--National Council (Episcopal Church).The Church Bulwark against Communism. (2 copies);--No Army, No Navy, No Air Force--Power of the Democratic Idea ("The Rockefeller Panel Report on American Democracy");--Report of the Conference of Chief Justices, Pasadena, California, August, 1958. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets S-U:--John H. Snow. The Case of Tyler Kent;--"Suppressed" Report Hearing (limitation of appellate juridiction of the US Supreme Court);-- 3 USGPO publications. US Congress committee reports on Communism. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets W-Z:--What's wrong in Washington?...;--"We Will Bury You!" (Communist threat);-- World Health Organization - pamphlet on the WHO produced by the Nat'l Defense Committee of the D.A.R. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Paradise Teacher Controversy-Article in Life, "Hell Breaks Loose in Paradise" (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Pasadena Groups (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - William Penn Patrick (candidate) (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Patriot Bookshop (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Patriot Bookshop -Pamphlets (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Patriotic Party (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Patriotic TV and Radio (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Peace Demonstrations -Clippings (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Pearl Harbor (US News & World Report article) (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Drew Pearson (columnist) (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - The Pentagon Case, by Col. Victor J.Fox (pseud. for Robert Winston) (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Petitions (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Police (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Police (JBS) - clippings (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Political (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Political (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Political Smears (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Political Smears (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Poor Richard's Bookshop (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Poor Richard's Bookshop (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Presbyterian Church (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Prayer Amendment-see also Religion in Schools (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Pro-America (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Project Alert (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Karl Prussion (and anti-Communist newsletters) (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Max Rafferty (US Senate campaign) (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Max Rafferty (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Ronald Reagan -speeches (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Reagan -friends (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Reagan -campaign workers (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Reagan -MM's lists of Reagan supporters (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Reagan -MM's notes on Reagan and Rousselot contributors (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Reagan -lists of Reagan contributors (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Reagan -R.L. Coate "Report on Reagan - An Exposé" (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Reagan -Coate and Cranston's views of Reagan (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Reagan -campaign for governor, committee lists (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Reagan -campaign for governor, committee lists (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Reagan -campaign for governor, committee lists (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Reagan -campaign for governor, committee lists (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Reagan -John Birch Society (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Reagan (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Reagan (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Reagan -as President1980s (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Religion in schools (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - "Republicans I" (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - "Republicans I" -literature (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - "Republicans II" -clippingsc1965-66 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - "Republicans II" -clippingsc1965-66 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Republican grps -letters and clippings (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Republicans -clippings1962-64 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Republicans -mailings (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Republicans -mailings1962-64 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Republicans -strategy clippings1962-63 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Republicans -clippings from LA Times (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Republicans -political groups1965-66 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Republicans -political groups1965-66 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Republican Citizens Committee (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Republican Good Government League1962 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Republican Good Government League (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Republican Good Government League (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Republicans -Calif. State GOP Central Committee1964 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Republicans -Arcadia Republicans, Inc. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Republicans -Arcadia Republicans, Inc.1961-66 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Republicans -Arcadia Republicans, Inc. (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Republicans -Arcadia Republicans, Inc. and Arcadia Republican Women's Club (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Republicans -Arcadia Republicans, Inc. and Arcadia Republican Women's Club (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Republicans -Arcadia Republican Women's Club (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Republicans -Arcadia Republican Women1965-66 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Republicans -Arcadia Republican Women1965-66 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Republicans -Republican Women (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Republicans -Republican Women1961-66 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Republicans -Republican Women1961-66 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Republicans -Republican Women -pamphlets (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Republicans -United Republicans of Calif. (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Republicans -UROP -clippings (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Republicans -UROP (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Republicans -UROP (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Republicans -Republican State [CA] Central Committee (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Republicans -Republican State Central Comm. (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Republicans -Republican State Central Comm. (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Bill Richardson -JBS names, primary doc. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Richardson -Hillings (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Richardson -Hillings (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Richardson -1966 campaign1966 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Richardson -1966 campaign -clippings1966 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Richardson -Senator1966-68 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Richardson -Louise Gelber1968 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Richardson (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Richardson -mat'l, JBS publications (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Richardson -mat'l, JBS publications (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Richardson -mat'l- Independent American (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Richardson (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Nelson Rockefeller (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Nelson Rockefeller -clippings (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - John H. Rousselot (conservative congressman) (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Rousselot1970 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Rousselot -clippings (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Rousselot -names (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Morrie Ryskind (columnist) (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Sample Ballot- 1964 electionsc1964 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Phyllis Schlafly (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Phyllis Schlafly -- Pamphlets (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Schools -Evolution -see also Education (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Schools -Little Lake Parents for Better Education (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Schools (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Schools (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Dr. Fred Schwartz - Christian anti-Communist Crusade (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Dr. Fred Schwartz (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Joe Shell (candidate for CA governor) (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Gerald L. K. Smith (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Gerald L. K. Smith -Christian Nat'list Crusade1961 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Gerald L. K. Smith -Christian Nat'list Crusade1962 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Gerald L. K. Smith -Christian Nat'list Crusade1962 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Gerald L. K. Smith -Christian Nat'list Crusade1963-64 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Gerald L. K. Smith -Christian Youth Against Communism (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Dan Smoot (journalist) - clipping (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Socialized Medicine (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Southern California Groups (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Southern California Groups (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Southern California Committee of Christian Laymen, Inc. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Southern California Committee of Christian Laymen, Inc. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Southern Poverty Law Center/Klanwatch (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Speakers - Local - Clippings (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - (CA) State Central Committee -see Republicans (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Adlai Stevenson (UN ambassador) - clippings1963 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Supreme Court (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - TACT (Truth about Civil Turmoil) -mailings and announcements (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - TACT and JBS (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - TACT clippings (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Taxation (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Taxation (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - George Todt (columnist) (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - George Todt (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Town Meeting for Democracy (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Truth Forum (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - United Congressional Appeal (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - United Nations (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - University of California Report 1966 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - US Constitution (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Congressman James Utt (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Wake Up America Rally -- Arcadia (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - General Edwin A. Walker (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - General Walker -military censorship (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - General Walker -military censorship -clippings (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - George Wallace -clippings1966-68 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - George Wallace -clippings1966-68 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - George Wallace -clippings1966-68 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - George Wallace -clippings1966-68 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - George Wallace -clippings 1966-68 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Watchdogs of Freedom (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Watchdog Groups (on Hate Groups)1980-90s (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Watchdog Groups 1980-90s (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Watchdog Groups 1980-90s (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Watchdog Groups 1980-90s (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - White Citizens' Council - literature, clippings (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - White Citizens' Council -clippings (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Wes Willoughby - see also Republican Groups (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - M. Meier's Notes, Alan Cranston (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Wes Willoughby-MM correspondence (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Dr. H.V. Witty (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Young Americans for Freedom (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Young Republicans (Box 35, Folder 1)
    (classed by city and some by year)
  - Young Republicans1961-66 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Young Republicans1961-66 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Arcadia Young Republicans (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - LA County Young Republicans-various newsletters (Box 35, Folder 4)
    -includes The Challenge 1965-66
  - LA County YR-resolutions, memos (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - LA County YR-resolutions, memos (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - LA County YR-resolutions, memos (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - LA County YR-resolutions, memos (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - LA County YR-resolutions, memos (Box 35, Folder 9)
    ---includes pamphlet "The Crisis of Freedom"
  - LA County YR-clippings, memos (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - JBS and LA Young Republicans (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - JBS Meetings and Young Republicans (Box 35, Folder 12)
- Series 2, Serials
  Series 2. Serials. is arranged alphabetically by title. Where deemed appropriate, some titles, mainly single issues, are located within the subject files series. An example of this exception would be a single issue of a serial that was collected because of its relevance to a specific subject. Newspapers, Series
  - ABC (Alliance for a Better Community), Monrovia, CA1963 - 1965 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - American Liberal (incorporated w/The Californian), San Francisco1962 July - Nov 1962 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - American Mercury, Torrance, CA1960 - 1961, 1967 - 1968 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - American Opinion (Robert Welch, ed.)1959-1963 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    incomplete
  - American Opinion1964 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - American Opinion1965 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - American Opinion1966 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - American Opinion1967 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - American Opinion1968 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - American Opinion1969 Jan 1969 Mar (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Awake! (Jehovah's Witnesses)1962 Mar (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - The Californian1961 Apr 1961 Aug (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - The Californian1961 Sept 1961 Dec (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - The Californian1962 Jan 1962 June) (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Correction, Please!, Belmont, MA1965 - 1965 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    3 issues
  - The Cross and the Flag (Gerald L.K. Smith)1961 - 1963 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - The Cross and the Flag1964 Jan 1964 July (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - The Cross and the Flag1964 Aug 1964 Nov (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Dan Smoot Report1960 - 1964 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Dixon Line (the Dixon Gayer Newsletter)1964 - 1965 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Dixon Line1966 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Dixon Line (now combined with Reason)1967 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Dixon Line1968 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Dixon Line1969 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Dixon Line1970 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Dixon Line1971 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Dixon Line1972 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Dixon Line1973 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Dixon Line1974 - 1975 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    stopped publication
  - Episcopal Review (incl. some clippings)ca.1964 - 1965 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Facts (ADL/B'nai B'rith publication)1962, 1966 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    2 issues
  - Facts in Education, Inc.1961, 1963 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    4 issues
  - Freedom Magazine (formerly American Progress) and The Freeman1960 July - 1960, 4 issues (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Frontier (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Homefront (Institute for American Democracy)1967 - 1968 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Homefront1969 - 1970 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Homefront1971 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Homefront1972 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Homefront1973 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Homefront1974 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Human Events (Box 41, Folder 7)
    -mat'ls about publication
  - Human Events1957 - 1962 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Human Events1962 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Human Events 1962 July 1962 Aug. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Human Events1962 Sept. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Human Events1963 June 1963 Aug. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Human EventsSept. 1963 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Human EventsOct. 1963 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Human Events1964 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Human Event1965 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - John Birch Society Bulletin 1962 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - John Birch Society Bulletin1963 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - John Birch Society Bulletin1964 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - John Birch Society Bulletin1965 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - John Birch Society Bulletin1966 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - John Birch Society Bulletin1967 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - John Birch Society Bulletin1967 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - John Birch Society Bulletin1968 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - John Birch Society Bulletin1969 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - LA Trunk Line (LA County Republican Central Committee)1961 - 1964 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - LA Trunk Line1964-1966 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Liberty Letter (Liberty Lobby publication)1963, 1966 - 1969 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - The Nation special issue on the radical right -"The Ultras"1962 July 30 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    (2 copies)
  - National Review1959, 1962 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    5 issues
  - National Review; National Review Bulletin1963 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    6 issues
  - National Review1965 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - National Review1965,1966 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - National Spotlight (continuation of Liberty Letter)1975 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Patriotic Preview1967 Feb 1967 Aug. (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Patriotic Preview1967 Sept. 1968 Apr. (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Patriotic Preview1968 May 1969 Jan. (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Progressive1961 Apr (Box 45, Folder 13)
    1 issue
  - Ramparts 1964 - 1968 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    incomplete (19 items)
  - Reason1965 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Reason1966 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Reports on UNESCO (Florence Fowler Lyons Reports)1959 Sept - 1960 Dec (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Review of the News1966 - 1970 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Tax Fax (Independent American/P. Courtney)1961 & n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Tax Fax1962 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Tax Fax1963 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Tax Fax1964 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Tax Fax1964 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Tax Fax1965 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Tax Fax1966 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Tax Fax1967 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Tax Fax1968 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Time1964 Nov 4 1965 Aug 20 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - TocsinVol. II:5,7 (c1961); April 1965 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    (3 copies)
  - Viewpoint1961 Oct. - 1963 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Washington Observer1967-68 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Patriotic Preview1963 June, 1963; Nov, 1965 Mar, 1966 Mar (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Patriotic Preview, MM's notes1966 Apr, 1967 Jan,1967 May (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Ebony1965 Aug (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Esquire1962 Aug (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Life1963 Apr 26, 1963 June 28, 1965 Mar 19,1965 Aug 27,1966 July 15,1942 Apr 13 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Look1961 Sept 26, 1962 Sept 25, 1965 Mar 23, 1965 Nov 16 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Saturday Evening Post1962 Dec 8 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Social Justice (Dr. Coughlin's publication)1939 July 17 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Series 3. Newspapers
  Series 3, are separated from other serials and arranged alphabetically. While the collection primarily contains newspapers of the extreme right, some radical left organs are also included.
  - Americans On Guard1961 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - American Standard1962 Oct 1, 1963 Jan 1963 Feb (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - California Independent1962 July (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - California Statesman1963 Mar, 1965 May (Box 6, Folder 4)
    7 issues
  - Catholic Worker,1961 Oct (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Citizen's Intelligence Digestc.a.1963 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Common Sense1961 Oct - 1967 Mar (Box 6, Folder 7)
    20 issues
  - Free Enterprise1964 Nov - 1967 June (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Herald Dispatch1965 July (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The Independent/The Californian1963 Jan - 1964 May (Box 6, Folder 10)
    16 issues
  - Mohammed Speaks1963 Sept, 1963 Nov (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - The Rail Splitter1963 Feb, 1963 Nov (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - San Gabriel Valley Citizen News1961 Dec (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Statecraft1969 Apr 5 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - The Student Statesman (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - The Sunday Ramparts1966 Oct, 1967 Jan (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Through to Victory1963 Sept (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - The Thunderbolt1962 Nov (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - The Valley Citizen,1963 June - 1963 Dec (Box 6, Folder 20)